<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on TC blog</title>
    <link>https://www.tczhong.com/categories/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on TC blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tczhong.com/categories/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intern Project</title>
      <link>https://www.tczhong.com/posts/project/intern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tczhong.com/posts/project/intern/</guid>
      <description>Intern Project In this summer, I am the intern from the Cloud infrastructure team in Walmart Sam&amp;rsquo;s Club and my manager is Ciby. My project is to design a scheduler to help developers to dynamically scale CosmosDB resource based on time.
Background and Problem I want to talk about some background information about my project. Azure Cosmos DB is a popular database among all application development teams in Sams. The billing of usage is based on Resource Unit configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve TimeZone in Azure Web App</title>
      <link>https://www.tczhong.com/posts/cc/azure-timezone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tczhong.com/posts/cc/azure-timezone/</guid>
      <description>TimeZone&amp;rsquo;s Problem In my intern project, I need to handle timezone problem. Because in US, there is Daylight time saving and 5 diffferent timezone. My code should provide service for people in different timezones. Therefore, in the front end, I could allow user input time in their own timezone, but I should save date and time in GMT+0. Then I could make sure all time in database is saved in the same timezone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve NoSuchMethodError in Azure JAVA SDK </title>
      <link>https://www.tczhong.com/posts/cc/azure-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tczhong.com/posts/cc/azure-error/</guid>
      <description>Problem I met a NoSuchMethodError in Azure Java SDK. The error message is like the following:
Exception in thread &amp;#34;main&amp;#34; java.lang.NoSuchMethodError: com.microsoft.azure.credentials.ApplicationTokenCredentials.proxy()Ljava/net/Proxy; It was very strange and I searched on the stackoverflow. And it shows the problem could be confliction in package version. Therefore I looked into the code to find the reason.
Solution In the beginning, I needed to go into the source code to see what happened there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
